Good evening everyone, welcome to the regular session
of the Hagerstown City Council.
Tonight we have several items on our agenda
including the community development grant.
Before we begin, I'd like to recognize
our city employees for their service.
We'll now open the floor for citizen comments.
Please state your name for the record.
Thank you Mayor. My name is John Smith
and I'd like to address the council about
traffic concerns on Dual Highway.
The intersection at Dual Highway and Eastern Boulevard
has become increasingly dangerous. We need a traffic study
to evaluate potential improvements.
Thank you Mr. Smith. Next we have Jane Doe.
Thank you. I want to commend the parks department
for the excellent maintenance of our city parks.
Moving on to action items. The first item is the
community development grant application for fifty
thousand dollars for neighborhood improvements.
I move to approve the grant application.
Second. All in favor? Motion carries five to zero.
Let the record show the grant is approved.
Next item is the first reading of Ordinance 25-01
regarding updated parking regulations in the
downtown district.
The ordinance would modify parking meter hours
and introduce a new residential parking permit
program for downtown residents.
Staff is requesting council guidance on budget
priorities for fiscal year 2026. We need direction
on capital improvement prioritization.
Now for our major discussion item. The proposed
ten million dollar infrastructure bond would fund
critical road and bridge repairs throughout the city.
This bond would address deferred maintenance on
approximately thirty miles of city roads and
twelve bridges that need structural repairs.
The estimated annual debt service would be
approximately eight hundred thousand dollars
funded through existing property tax revenue.
Council members expressed support for the concept
but requested additional analysis of the impact
on the city's bond rating and debt capacity.
Our second major discussion topic is the affordable
housing initiative. Staff is proposing new requirements
for developers building more than twenty units.
The proposal would require ten percent of units
to be designated as affordable at eighty percent
of area median income.
Several council members raised concerns about
the impact on development costs and whether this
could discourage new construction.
In conclusion, the next regular session is scheduled
for February 18, 2025. Thank you all for attending.
This meeting is adjourned.